Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
- Correspondence, 1963-2004, Series 1; Boxes 1 - 64
  - Literary correspondence, 1964-2003, Subseries 1.2; Boxes 37 - 44
    - Murphy, Hayden, 1978-2003 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Ni Dhomhnaill, Nuala, undated; 1987 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - O'Brien Connor Cruise, 1977-2002 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, 1970-1983 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, 1984-1989 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, 1990-2000 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - O'Brien, Edna, undated; 1989-1998 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - O'Donoghue, Bernard, undated 1972-2002 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - O'Driscoll, Dennis, undated; 1979-2001 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - O'Flynn, Liam, 1997-2001 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - O'Grady, Desmond, 1984-2003 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Ormsby, Frank, 1978-ca. 1999 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Paulin, Tom, 1982-2002 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Pearson, Henry, 1978-1990 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Pinsky, Robert, 1979-2000 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Raine, Craig, undated; 1980-2002 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Rawling, Tom, 1981-1989 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Simic, Charles, 1989-1996 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Simmons, James, undated; 1968-1997 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Sleigh, Tom, 1985-2001 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Dave, 1979-1994 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Snodgrass, W.D., 1986 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Snyder, Gary, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Stallworthy, Jon, 1980-2002 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Steele, Jon, 1984-2001 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Sweeney, Jack, 1965-1985 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Sweeney, Matthew, 1991-2001 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Thwaite, Anthony, 1964-2002 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Tillinghast, Richard, undated; 1977-2002 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Walcott, Derek, undated; 1995-2001 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Watson, George, 1983-1989 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Welch, Robert, 1994-2001 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1968-2004, Subseries 1.3; Boxes 45 - 53
    - 1960s (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 1970s (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 1980-1984 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - 1985-1989 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - 1990 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - 1991 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - 1992 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - 1993 January-September (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - 1993 October-December (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - ca. 1994 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - 1994 January-April (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - 1994 May-June (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - 1994 July-August (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - 1994 September-October (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 1994 November-December (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - ca. 1995 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - 1995 January (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - 1995 February (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - 1995 March (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - 1995 April-May (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - 1995 June (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - 1995 July (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - 1995 August (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - 1995 September (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - 1995 October (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - 1995 November (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - 1995 December (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - 1996 January (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 1996 February (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - 1996 March (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - 1996 April-May (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - 1996 June-August (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - 1996 September-December (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - ca. 1997 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - 1997 January (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - 1997 February (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - 1997 March (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - 1997 April (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - 1997 May-June (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - 1997 July (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - 1997 August (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 1997 September (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - 1997 October (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - 1997 November-December (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - ca. 1998 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - 1998 January-March (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - 1998 April-May (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - 1998 June-July (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - 1998 August-September (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - 1998 October (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - 1998 November-December (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - ca. 1999 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - 1999 January-March (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - 1999 April-June (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - 1999 July-August (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - 1999 September-October (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - 1999 November-December (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - ca. 2000 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - 2000 January (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - 2000 February (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - 2000 March-April (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - 2000 May-June (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 2000 July (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - 2000 August (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - 2000 September (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 2000 October (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - 2000 November-December (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - ca. 2001 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - 2001 January-February (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - 2001 March (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - 2001 April (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 2001 May (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 2001 June (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 2001 July-August (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 2001 September (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - 2001 October (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - 2001 November-December (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - ca. 2002 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - 2002 January (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - 2002 February (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - 2002 March (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - 2002 April (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - 2002 May (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - 2002 June (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - 2002 July (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - 2002 August (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - 2002 September-October (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - 2002 November (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - 2002 December (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - undated (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - drafts of dictated letters, undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - fragments (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - form letter to persons sending manuscripts for evaluation (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Other correspondence, 1967-2003, Subseries 1.4; Boxes 54 - 64
    Arranged by type of correspondence, then in chronological order.
    - Appearances declined
    - 1994 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - 1996 January-February (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - 1996 March-April (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - 1996 May-June (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - 1996 July-December (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - 1997 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - 1998 January-April (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - 1998 May-August (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - 1998 September (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - 1998 October (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - 1998 November (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - 1998 December (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - 1999 January (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - 1999 February (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - 1999 March (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - 1999 April (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - 1999 May (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - 1999 June (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - 1999 July (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - 1999 August (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - 1999 September (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - 1999 October (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - 1999 November (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - 1999 December (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - 2000 January (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - 2000 February (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - 2000 March (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - 2000 April (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - 2000 May (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - 2000 June (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - 2000 July-August (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - 2000 September (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - 2000 October-November (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - 2000 December (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - 2001 January (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - 2001 February-March (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - 2001 April-May (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - 2001 June-July (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - 2001 August (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - 2001 September (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - 2001 October (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - 2001 November (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - 2001 December (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - 2002 January (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - 2002 February (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - 2002 March (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - 2002 April (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - 2002 May (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - 2002 June-August (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - 2002 September-December (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Publishers correspondence
    - Agenda, 1984-1995 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - The Atlanta Monthly, 1970-2000 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1997-2001 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - David R. Godine, 1980-1987 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - The Dolmen Press Limited, 1970-1971 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - The Dublin Review, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1965-1969 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1970s (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1980s (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1990-1993 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1994-1995 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1996-1997 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1998-2000 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 2001-2003 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux, undated and 1970s (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1980s (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1990s (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 2000s (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - The Macmillan Publishers Ltd (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Martin Secker & Warburg, 1988-1989 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - The New York Review of Books, 1979-2002 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - The New Yorker, 1970-2002 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Oxford University Press, 1970-1993 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Parnassus: Poetry in Review, 1982-1995 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Poetry, 1995 and undated (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Poetry Ireland, 1995-2002 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - The Southern Review, 1994-1995 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - The Times Literary Supplement, 1987-2002 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - University of York, 1991-1992 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - W.W. Norton & Company, 1977-2000 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, undated (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, 1960s (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, 1970s (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, 1980s (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, 1990s (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, 2000s (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation correspondence
    - 1967-1979 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - 1970s (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - 1980s (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - 1994-1999 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Invitations
    - Year unknown (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - 1960s (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - 1970s (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - 1980s [1 of 2] (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - 1980s [2 of 2] (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - 1990s [1 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - 1990s [2 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - 1990s [3 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - 2000s [1 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - 2000s [2 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - 2000s [3 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Recommendations [Restricted]
    - A-B (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - C (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - D (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - E-F (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - G (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - H-Hi (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Ho-Hu (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - I-J (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - K-L (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - M (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - N-O (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - P-Q (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - R (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - S (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - T-U (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - V (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - W (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - X-Z (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Fragments (Box 64, Folder 10)
- Writings by others, 1964-2004, Series 2; Boxes 65 – 73 and OP9
  The series includes a large number of writings about Seamus Heaney as well as writings about a variety of other subjects from 1964-2004. The majority of the writings about Heaney consist of reviews and translations of his work, essays, and poems about him. Other writings include poems, reviews, scripts, translations, essays and other prose. These manuscripts, which may be photocopies, original holographs, or typescripts, often have accompanying letters. The writings are arranged in alphabetical order by author, and include writings by Joseph Brodsky, Patrick Crotty, Donald Davie, Seamus Deane, Ted Hughes, Patrick Kavanagh, Michael Longley, Medbh McGuckian, Derek Mahon, Paul Muldoon, and James Simmons. Of particular interest is a collection of poems written by Ted Hughes, the majority of which are included in Birthday Letters, and a large number of early poems by Michael Longley, some of which are holograph manuscripts signed by Longley.
  Organized into two subseries: (2.1) Writings about Seamus Heaney and (2.2) Other writings.
  - Writings about Seamus Heaney, 1972-2002, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 65 - 67
    - Anonymous, "All I Believe That Happened There Was Revision: Selected Poems 1965-1975 and New Selected Poems, 1966-1987," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Anonymous, Bibliographies of writings by Seamus Heaney (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Anonymous, Draft blurb for Redress of Poetry, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Anonymous, Introduction of Seamus Heaney for awarding of honorary Doctor of Humane Letters, Chestnut Hill College, photocopied typescript, 10 May 1986 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Anonymous, "Memento," poem for Seamus and Marie Heaney, holograph manuscript (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Anonymous, "On the Visit of Mr. Seamus Heaney, 23.10.72," poem, typescript (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Anonymous, "191 Strand Road," poem for Marie and Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript, 1979 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Anonymous, "The Potato Bard, An Inner Émigré's Reading of Seamus Heaney's Selected Poems 1965-1975," photocopied typescript, 1995 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Anonymous, "Raspberry-Picking," poem for Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Anonymous, "IX Seamus Heaney," photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Anonymous, "Seamus Heaney- Personal Profile" photocopied typescript with letter, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Anonymous, "Sweeney Astray, Part 1: Seamus Heaney's translation of the Irish Epic Buile Suibhne," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Anonymous, Untitled article on the poetry of Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript with revisions (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Anonymous, Untitled article [fragment] on Heaney's poetry, includes bibliography, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Anonymous, Untitled poem "for Seamus and Marie on their anniversary," typescript, signed, 6 August 1999 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Anonymous, Welcome speech for Seamus Heaney Edinburgh Lectures: 3 February 2001, photocopied typescript with holograph notes (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Alcorn, Roy, "Union," poem, typescript, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Barnes, Alan, "Seamus Heaney: The Poet and 'the troubles,'" photocopied typescript with letter from the author (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Bartha, Michel, translator, "Le Suiveur," translation into French of Seamus Heaney's "The Follower," photocopied typescript with holograph notes (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Boylan, Patricia, "A Poem," (September 1997 at the Kerlin Gallery), photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Buttel, Robert, "Seamus Heaney," biography submitted for DLB: British Poets, 21 March 1983, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - Buttel, Robert, "Seamus Heaney," photocopied typescript, pp. 1-66a (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - Cleary, A.A., Untitled article regarding Field Day Publications, [includes discussion of Heaney's "Open Letter" and "Sweeney Astray"] incomplete, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Colome, Pura Lopez, translator, "El Nivel," translation into Spanish of Seamus Heaney's The Spirit Level, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - Cooper, Glenda Patton, "To Seamus Heaney," poem, photocopied typescript, sighed by author, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - Cotter, Aoife, "Heaney's Visit," poem," In remembrance of Seamus Heaney's visit to Muckross on Tuesday 31 January 1995, photocopied typescript (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - Desmond, John, "Another Light," poem for Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript, 1999 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Desmond, John F., "From Ireland to the World: Seamus Heaney's Journeys to Imagined Places," typescript with some revisions (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Doocey, Roberta A., "Seamus Heaney: The Apprenticeship of a Poet," student paper, photocopied typescript, 1978 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Durcan, Paul, "For Seamus Heaney on His 50th Birthday," poem, typescript with note from the author, 13 April 1989 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Feeney, Mary, translator, "L'Homme de Tollund" translation into French of Seamus Heaney's "Tollund Man" from Wintering Out and "Nord," translation of Heaney's "North" from the collection North, typescript (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Fitzpatrick, Mary, "An Act of Union- The Poetry of Seamus Heaney," student paper, photocopied typescript with two letters, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Frear, Graham S., "Black House," poem written for Seamus Heaney after reading the Spirit Level, typescript with note from author (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - French, Elaine Warren, "An Ode to Seamus Heaney," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Gewanter, David, "Legislators of Poetry" (tentative title), review of The Government of the Tongue by Seamus Heaney, and Poetry and the World by Robert Pinsky photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Golden, Virginia, "Homage," holograph poem about Seamus Heaney with illustration, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Graecen, Robert, "Sunday Sequence," a note on Seamus Heaney for Radio Ulster (BBC), photocopied typescript, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Groupe d'Estudes et de Recherche Britanniques de l'Universite de Bordeaux III, translation into French of "From the Republic of Conscience" by Seamus Heaney, typescript with photocopied English poem (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Haffenden, John, "Seamus Heaney and the Feminine Sensibility," essay, carbon copy with letter, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Hamblin, Robert "What I Would Have Said to Seamus Heaney," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Hay, Colleen, "Irish Girl: Inspired," poem, typescript, 2002 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Henigan, Julie, "Sweeney in Glen Bolcain," poem "after Seamus Heaney's 'Sweeney Astray,'" photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Hennedy, Hugh, "By Way of Seamus and Aideen," and "Essay of Emendation," poems, photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Hildebidle, John, "Troubles," poem for Seamus Heaney, typescript, signed (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Hill, Annette, "'The Music of What Happens:' Religious Faith in Seamus Heaney's 'Seeing Things'" student paper, photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Hingerty, Kay, "Ulster Youth Theatre's 'Stations' based around Seamus Heaney's 'Station Island,'" typescript for newspaper article with published article, 1990 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Hinton, Brian [?], "Chapter Two: Legend as Archetype: the Poetry of Seamus Heaney," Ph.D. dissertation, photocopied typescript, 1981 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Hobsbaum, Philip, interview on Seamus Heaney's Wintering Out, interviewer: [?] O'Mahony, 19 November [??] (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - Hong, Julie, "To Be Silent Is to be No One: The Maturation of Heaney's Speaker from 'Punishment' to 'Oysters,'" student paper, 2002 (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - Huyghebaert, Marianne, "Seamus among the Shades: A Translation and an Analysis of Seamus Heaney's 'Station Island,'" dissertation, photocopied typescript, 1988 (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - Jagger, Helen, "The Poetry of Seamus Heaney," photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - Kearney, Richard, "Heaney and Homecoming: A Modernist Perspective," photocopied typescript with revisions (Box 66, Folder 26)
    - Kearney, Richard, "Ireland's communities- From the Global to the Local," [mentions Seamus Heaney], photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 27)
    - Kearney, Richard, "Thought and Poetry: Martin Heidegger and Seamus Heaney," photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 28)
    - Kelly, H.A., "Seamus Heaney's Erratic Sweeney," typescript with letter from author, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - Killiam, Paul, "Villanelle for an Ovum Churner," poem, typescript (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - Kobiernicki, Leszek, article on Field Work, photocopied typescript (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - Macrae, A.D.F., speech about Heaney, typescript, June 1990 (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - McDiarmid, Lucy, " The Government of the Tongue: The 1986 T.S. Eliot Memorial Lectures and Other Critical Writings," review, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - McEvoy, Iris, "Seamus Heaney," typescript, 1996 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - McGrail, Steven [?], "Steven McGrail & Seamus Heaney," unedited poem, typescript (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Meir, Colin, "Territorial Epics: Recent Narrative Verse by Seamus Heaney and John Montague," photocopied typescript, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Menashe, Samuel, collection of poems inscribed "For Seamus Heaney, Unshaken," typescript, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Morgan, Calvert A., "The 1997 Common Wealth Awards," (Seamus Heaney, recipient of the Literature Award), photocopied script, 5 April 1997 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Morrison, Blake, "Seamus Heaney," for Methuen Contemporary Writers Series, carbon typescript with holograph corrections (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Murphy, Gerry, "Pushkin's Arion (after Heaney)," poem, photocopied typescript, 2000 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Niven [?], Untitled poem regarding Seamus Heaney's poetry, 12 November 2000 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Nohrnberg, Peter C.L., "Poetry of the Deliberate: Seamus Heaney's North," dissertation, 1995 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, "Seamus Heaney and Dante," photocopied typescript with revisions and letter from the author, 1992 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, "Seamus Heaney and Wordsworth, A Correspondent Breeze," photocopied typescript with revisions (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - O'Shea, Helen, Transcript of interview with Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript, 1 October 1979 with published article from Quadrant, September 1981 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Parini, Jay, "Island," poem for Seamus and Marie Heaney, signed, photocopied typescript (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Parini, Jay, "Seamus Heaney: The Ground Possessed," photocopied typescript and photocopy of published article from The Southern Review, ca. 1979 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Parker, Michael, Seamus Heaney: the Making of the Poet, chapter 5: "Quickenings 1975-1984," photocopied typescript with notes (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - de Petris, Carla, "Heaney and Dante: the Road from Pisa to Lough Derg," photocopied typescript (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Pratt, Charles, Introduction of Seamus Heaney at Phillips Exeter Academy reading, 15 May 1985, photocopied typescript (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Radford, Colin, address delivered at Queen's University [Belfast] to honor Seamus Heaney [recipient of Doctor of Literature, honoris causa), 7 July 1982, typescript with revisions and note (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Regan, Jennifer, "Romantic Ireland's Dead and Gone, But at a Party at the Carlyle Hotel the Poetic Tradition Lives On," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Rosen, Michael J., review of Station Island with letter from the author, photocopied typescript, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - Routley, Nicholas, "Like Snow," five songs for baritone and piano to poems by Seamus Heaney and Robert Graves, photocopied music score (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Ryan, Peter, Transcript of interview with Seamus Heaney at Cambridge Poetry Festival, typescript with letter from interviewer, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - Savant, John, "Rats!" poem for Seamus Heaney, typescript (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - Scanlan, Thomas J.," The Music of What Happens: The Voice of Seamus Heaney," honors paper [Harvard College], photocopied typescript, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - Scott, Leslie, "Northman," poem for Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - Sharkey, Patricia, "On Hearing Heaney Read 'The Beseiged City,'" poem, photocopied typescript (Box 67, Folder 27)